<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stuart nelson</title>
    <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on stuart nelson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:09:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stuartnelson.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paycheck Disconnect</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/paycheck-disconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:09:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/paycheck-disconnect/</guid>
      <description>This post was inspired by Future100: Design Students Rethink the Commons.
Background As I finished reading the above post, I reached the final section that was listing the architects who had been mentioned, and where they hailed from. At that moment, when I thought about life as a professor at a university (not that any of the people mentioned are professors, it&amp;rsquo;s just the idea as it occurred to me), I was thinking about how they feel about their salary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tattoo Day</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/tattoo-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 10:47:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/tattoo-day/</guid>
      <description>Location: Warsaw
I had a tattoo appointment today.
On my tattoo selection I originally wanted a tattoo for my proposed trip to vietnam, which was meant to be happening at this point in time.1 As that trip had been scuttled and I still wanted a tattoo, I started looking through a best tattoo shop list for warsaw. I looked through dozens of artists&#39; instagram pages.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warsaw Uprising Museum</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/warsaw-uprising-museum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 11:38:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/warsaw-uprising-museum/</guid>
      <description>Location: Warsaw
Note to the reader: I only wrote a single sentence for this day&amp;rsquo;s entry, despite having gone to the Warsaw Uprising museum. I&amp;rsquo;ve included that sentence, but this is a post almost entirely of pictures.
You can miss something but not want it.
Photos Sign hanging over the entrance into the museum.  This sign was used to separate poles from germans. the nazis had studied the jim crow south to learn how to segregate people, so seeing the equivalent of &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Tour</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/walking-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 10:33:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/walking-tour/</guid>
      <description>Location: Warsaw
There&amp;rsquo;s an awesome market hall right by my airbnb, Hala Mirowska. I grabbed a large rectangular pastry filled with cheese and spinach for breakfast. They had about 8 different kinds, and I want to try tme all.
The market hall. It was open every day and always full of people shopping.  I took a long walk to the reconstructed old town, and walked from its southernmost end up to the northernmost, then headed back south on a path along the river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warsaw Calling</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/warsaw-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 16:33:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/warsaw-calling/</guid>
      <description>Location: Berlin -&amp;gt; Warsaw
The train from Berlin to Warsaw was less than eventful. The train was direct, I had some music, and they were handing out free water. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t be easier.
After a simple airbnb check-in, I scoped out a route to the tourist area full of restaurants I remembered from my previous trip, and headed out to find some dinner.
Poland has this concept called a &amp;ldquo;milk bar&amp;rdquo;. Originally serving dairy products, they now (and for a long time) serve all sorts of traditional polish foods &amp;ndash; cabbage, potatoes, breaded fried pork cutlets, pierogi &amp;ndash; at a crazy low, government-subsidized, cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescue From Without</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rescue-from-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 13:49:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rescue-from-without/</guid>
      <description>Location: Bastogne -&amp;gt; Liege -&amp;gt; Aachen -&amp;gt; Berlin
I got to the bus station to buy a ticket, only to discover that the machine requires a certain MoBIB membership card, which you load trips on. Sounds more or less like an oyster card in london. Because of covid, buses aren&amp;rsquo;t accepting cash. Frantically, with time ticking down, I attempted to register online for one of these cards. Once you register and order a card, you can start putting trips onto your account, and then ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nuts!</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/nuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 14:00:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/nuts/</guid>
      <description>Location: Bastogne
I woke up feeling like something was off.
Not so much wanderlust as much as fernweh, despite being away from &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo;. When I left the house last night for dinner, my hostess was watching tv on the couch. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m simply in a home that&amp;rsquo;s bothering me. Which is a weird thing to contemplate.
I walked to the bastogne war museum. I thought it was about the battle of the bulge, but it covered the run up to WW2, starting with the end of WW1, and all the way through to the war&amp;rsquo;s end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No More Camping</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/no-more-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 13:43:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/no-more-camping/</guid>
      <description>Location: Ochamp -&amp;gt; Bastogne
Not much to say about today. I woke up around 8am. My destination was only 2 hours away, and the check-in time was 5pm.
I hung out at my &amp;ldquo;campsite&amp;rdquo; reading and watching &amp;ldquo;no reservations&amp;rdquo; until noon or so. I had three pints left over from the previous day, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to bike with that with me. So there was some morning drinking.
The ride followed a &amp;ldquo;pre&amp;rdquo; ravel route.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Belgium</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/back-to-belgium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 13:01:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/back-to-belgium/</guid>
      <description>Location: Reims -&amp;gt; Charleville-Mézière -&amp;gt; Fumay -&amp;gt; Ochamp
I&amp;rsquo;m returning to camping today. And biking. I&amp;rsquo;ve literally only been away from it for two days, but the whole idea already seems weird. And I had been camping for two weeks.
Rain and storms are coming in the rest of the week, starting in a day or two. At great financial cost (comparatively .. 40EUR/night vs. camping for ~5EUR/night) I took a room in Bastogne for the remainder of the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Day in Reims</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-day-in-reims/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 11:54:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-day-in-reims/</guid>
      <description>Location: Reims
I woke up and had coffee in the airbnb. That was a delightful way to start the day. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be interesting going back to camping, albeit for only one night.
I started considering my next residence after this bike trip. I was planning on Warsaw / Krakow, but actually a month rental in Paris is under 1000EUR, and pretty centrally located. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely something to consider, but the cost of everything will be a lot more &amp;ndash; probably 2-3x more than Poland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconnecting With a Friend</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/reconnecting-with-a-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 13:03:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/reconnecting-with-a-friend/</guid>
      <description>Location: Charleville-Mézière -&amp;gt; Reims
First, Reims is pronounced like &amp;ldquo;Raas&amp;rdquo;. Or so. Knowing that would have been helpful when telling people where I was going. &amp;ldquo;Remmes&amp;rdquo;, as I had been pronouncing it, does not exist.
I had a very slow start to the day. My bus to Reims left at 15:27, and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much going on in CM on a saturday morning.
The bus to Reims was uneventful. I listened to, for the umpteenth time, Colour Haze&amp;rsquo;s self-titled album.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taste of Civilization</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/taste-of-civilization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 11:39:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/taste-of-civilization/</guid>
      <description>Location: Revin -&amp;gt; Charleville-Mézière
The ride today was a non-event. It was 44km of, again, pristine paved voie verte. I reached my destination very quickly. Along the way I passed several little pillboxes facing north upriver. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing it was to harass an attempt at nazi incursion into france.
At most soldiers stationed inside could have harried incoming transports. I&#39;m guessing they were primarily there to inform of an invasion. By noon I was in Charleville-Mézière.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Rest Day</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/another-rest-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 13:15:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/another-rest-day/</guid>
      <description>Location: Revin -&amp;gt; Monthermé -&amp;gt; Tournavaux -&amp;gt; Revin
Today I was going to stay in the area and go for a hike. The river was flanked by fantastically forested hills, the sky was clear, and the temperature peaked at 24C (sweet, sweet respite).
The original path I looked at turned out to be for mountain bikes. And, at 20km, it was more than I wanted to hike on a day off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel Companion</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/travel-companion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 09:50:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/travel-companion/</guid>
      <description>Location: Givet -&amp;gt; Revin
Today was planned as an easy day. The voie verte route starts in Givet and passes right through Revin. In total, I was going to bike about 35km of the route to reach my destination.
Within about 20min of leaving, I rode past a guy with a touring setup similar to mine while he was having some water. A bit later I stopped to take a picture and he rolled past me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Friendly Detour</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-friendly-detour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 12:36:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-friendly-detour/</guid>
      <description>Location: Jemelle -&amp;gt; Houyot -&amp;gt; Beauraing -&amp;gt; Givet
I woke up to being a little cold and it being mostly dark. How? But how? It&amp;rsquo;s 17C! I checked my phone: 6:30am. Ah, well I still got 8 hours of sleep. I snoozed until 8:30am. The bike repair shop (remember I had unhooked my front brakes?) didn&amp;rsquo;t open until 9:30am.
I got up and packed. My breakfast was 3 belgian waffles and the remaining brown beer from Saint Monon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off to the Brewery</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/off-to-the-brewery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 11:41:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/off-to-the-brewery/</guid>
      <description>Location: La Roche-en-Ardenne -&amp;gt; Hotton -&amp;gt; Jemelle
I originally had scheduled 90 km for today. Then, upon seeing the high temp for the day (32C), I scaled it back to 50km. I arrived in Jemelle feeling good. I even did another 15km rountrip to get beer from Saint Monon Brewery, but now I can feel the ride.
I followed the EV5 bike route the entire way, an international European route. Well marked, well maintained, it was good riding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going for a Hike</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/going-for-a-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 10:31:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/going-for-a-hike/</guid>
      <description>Location: La Roche-en-Ardenne
After yesterday&amp;rsquo;s complete rest day, I found a &amp;ldquo;challenging&amp;rdquo; hike in the area using komoot.
Either their algorithm for calculting difficulty is off (probable) or I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten in a lot better shape (less likely). The 10-ish km I hiked were not challenging; I hardly broke a sweat. It was all in the forest, which was nice, but absent more than the occasional hilly view, not much was going on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest Day</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rest-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 16:13:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rest-day/</guid>
      <description>Location: La Roche-en-Ardenne
Corneal and Joke left before I woke up. They were super nice; I was bummed I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to say goodbye.
The night before they told me to go to the tourist center and grab a RAVeL map, short for route à vélo longue. I had been following some of these routes without knowing it, and having an official map sounded like a good idea.
La Roche-en-Ardenne is such a cute town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overloaded</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/overloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 19:15:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/overloaded/</guid>
      <description>Location: Viersalm -&amp;gt; La Roche-en-Ardenne
&amp;ldquo;Jettison some weight, or I&amp;rsquo;ll never make it to Cybertron!&amp;rdquo;
Astrotrain couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more right.
The day started well, despite a 9C night that woke me up cold. Tonight it will be cold again, but the nights get warmer after that. I&amp;rsquo;ll try stuffing extra clothing into my sleeping bag tonight to keep warm. Like a hobo.1
My plan for today was to head to Saint-Hubert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Smoother Path</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-smoother-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 15:08:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-smoother-path/</guid>
      <description>Location: Sourbrodt -&amp;gt; Viersalm
It rained several times in the night. Despite my inability as an outdoorsman, my tarp kept me dry. Except for waking up cold between 5am and 7am (cf. previous comment on bivouac sacks), I slept well.
I broke camp around 9:30am. I had only drunk two of the three beers from the previous night, so I had a Leffe with breakfast. Breakfast was a bit of peanut butter with some dried cranberries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rough Going</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rough-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 14:16:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rough-going/</guid>
      <description>Location: Lac Gileppe -&amp;gt; Sourbrodt
I broke camp early and ate my leftover sandwich that I bought in Aachen HBF. It was bread and camembert, and would become my diet for the next three weeks (although I did not know this at the time).
The biking was brutal uphill. I had been &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; in the previous months, but 15 sets of 3min hill runs do not come close to preparing you for a 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure Begins</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/the-adventure-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:24:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/the-adventure-begins/</guid>
      <description>Location: Berlin -&amp;gt; Aachen -&amp;gt; Lac Gileppe
Long travel day. After a tearful goodbye with my hetero life partner Lukas, we were off to the races. Berlin HBF to be exact.
The train from HBF to Bad Oeynhausen (yeah, seriously) was easy. From there, transfer to a regional train to Düsseldorf HBF. This is where it got interesting.
Halfway through the three or so hour ride, there was a train blocking the track (between Oelde and Neubeckum).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Day Homeless</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/first-day-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:52:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/first-day-homeless/</guid>
      <description>Location: Berlin
Officially I&amp;rsquo;ve been unemployed for one week. Because I was still in my apartment, still working (small project generating sales reports for bräugier), still leading my normal life, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like anything had changed.
Yesterday evening I handed over my keys to my apartment, put my bags on my bike, and became homeless.
(I&amp;rsquo;m staying two nights with Lukas, but officially, I have no place of my own)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>This is my about me page.
I very rarely write things, and never about technology.
I work as a software developer, but prefer skiing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
