<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>warsaw on stuart&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/tags/warsaw/</link>
    <description>Recent content in warsaw on stuart&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 10:47:52 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://stuartnelson3.github.io/tags/warsaw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tattoo Day</title>
      <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/tattoo-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 10:47:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/tattoo-day/</guid>
      <description>Location: Warsaw
I had a tattoo appointment today.
On my tattoo selection I originally wanted a tattoo for my proposed trip to vietnam, which was meant to be happening at this point in time.1 As that trip had been scuttled and I still wanted a tattoo, I started looking through a best tattoo shop list for warsaw. I looked through dozens of artists&amp;rsquo; instagram pages.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking Tour</title>
      <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/walking-tour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 10:33:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/walking-tour/</guid>
      <description>Location: Warsaw
There&amp;rsquo;s an awesome market hall right by my airbnb, Hala Mirowska. I grabbed a large rectangular pastry filled with cheese and spinach for breakfast. They had about 8 different kinds, and I want to try tme all.
The market hall. It was open every day and always full of people shopping.  I took a long walk to the reconstructed old town, and walked from its southernmost end up to the northernmost, then headed back south on a path along the river.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warsaw Calling</title>
      <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/warsaw-calling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 16:33:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/warsaw-calling/</guid>
      <description>Location: Berlin -&amp;gt; Warsaw
The train from Berlin to Warsaw was less than eventful. The train was direct, I had some music, and they were handing out free water. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t be easier.
After a simple airbnb check-in, I scoped out a route to the tourist area full of restaurants I remembered from my previous trip, and headed out to find some dinner.
Poland has this concept called a &amp;ldquo;milk bar&amp;rdquo;. Originally serving dairy products, they now (and for a long time) serve all sorts of traditional polish foods &amp;ndash; cabbage, potatoes, breaded fried pork cutlets, pierogi &amp;ndash; at a crazy low, government-subsidized, cost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>