<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on stuart&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on stuart&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 19:15:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overloaded</title>
      <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/overloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 19:15:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/overloaded/</guid>
      <description>Location: Viersalm -&amp;gt; La Roche-en-Ardenne
&amp;ldquo;Jettison some weight, or I&amp;rsquo;ll never make it to Cybertron!&amp;rdquo;
Astrotrain couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more right.
The day started well, despite a 9C night that woke me up cold. Tonight it will be cold again, but the nights get warmer after that. I&amp;rsquo;ll try stuffing extra clothing into my sleeping bag tonight to keep warm. Like a hobo.1
My plan for today was to head to Saint-Hubert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Smoother Path</title>
      <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/a-smoother-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 15:08:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/a-smoother-path/</guid>
      <description>Location: Sourbrodt -&amp;gt; Viersalm
It rained several times in the night. Despite my inability as an outdoorsman, my tarp kept me dry. Except for waking up cold between 5am and 7am (cf. previous comment on bivouac sacks), I slept well.
I broke camp around 9:30am. I had only drunk two of the three beers from the previous night, so I had a Leffe with breakfast. Breakfast was a bit of peanut butter with some dried cranberries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rough Going</title>
      <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/rough-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 14:16:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/rough-going/</guid>
      <description>Location: Lac Gileppe -&amp;gt; Sourbrodt
I broke camp early and ate my leftover sandwich that I bought in Aachen HBF. It was bread and camembert, and would become my diet for the next three weeks (although I did not know this at the time).
The biking was brutal uphill. I had been &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; in the previous months, but 15 sets of 3min hill runs do not come close to preparing you for a 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure Begins</title>
      <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/the-adventure-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 11:24:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/the-adventure-begins/</guid>
      <description>Location: Berlin -&amp;gt; Aachen -&amp;gt; Lac Gileppe
Long travel day. After a tearful goodbye with my hetero life partner Lukas, we were off to the races. Berlin HBF to be exact.
The train from HBF to Bad Oeynhausen (yeah, seriously) was easy. From there, transfer to a regional train to Düsseldorf HBF. This is where it got interesting.
Halfway through the three or so hour ride, there was a train blocking the track (between Oelde and Neubeckum).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Day Homeless</title>
      <link>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/first-day-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 10:52:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stuartnelson3.github.io/posts/first-day-homeless/</guid>
      <description>Location: Berlin
Officially I&amp;rsquo;ve been unemployed for one week. Because I was still in my apartment, still working (small project generating sales reports for bräugier), still leading my normal life, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like anything had changed.
Yesterday evening I handed over my keys to my apartment, put my bags on my bike, and became homeless.
(I&amp;rsquo;m staying two nights with Lukas, but officially, I have no place of my own)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>