<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biketrip on stuart nelson</title>
    <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/tags/biketrip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biketrip on stuart nelson</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 13:49:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://stuartnelson.xyz/tags/biketrip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rescue From Without</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rescue-from-without/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 13:49:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rescue-from-without/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Bastogne -&amp;gt; Liege -&amp;gt; Aachen -&amp;gt; Berlin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got to the bus station to buy a ticket, only to discover that the machine&#xA;requires a certain MoBIB membership card, which you load trips on. Sounds&#xA;more or less like an oyster card in london. Because of covid, buses aren&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;accepting cash. Frantically, with time ticking down, I attempted to register&#xA;online for one of these cards. Once you register and order a card, you can&#xA;start putting trips onto your account, and then ride. I registered and then&#xA;searched the site in vain, finding no way to order a card. With 5min to go&#xA;before the bus showed up, I died to throw myself at the driver&amp;rsquo;s mercy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuts!</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/nuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 14:00:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/nuts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Bastogne&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I woke up feeling like something was off.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not so much wanderlust as much as fernweh, despite being away from &amp;ldquo;home&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;When I left the house last night for dinner, my hostess was watching tv on&#xA;the couch. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m simply in a home that&amp;rsquo;s bothering me.&#xA;Which is a weird thing to contemplate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I walked to the bastogne war museum. I thought it was about the battle of the&#xA;bulge, but it covered the run up to WW2, starting with the end of WW1, and&#xA;all the way through to the war&amp;rsquo;s end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No More Camping</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/no-more-camping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 13:43:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/no-more-camping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Ochamp -&amp;gt; Bastogne&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not much to say about today. I woke up around 8am. My destination was only 2&#xA;hours away, and the check-in time was 5pm.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hung out at my &amp;ldquo;campsite&amp;rdquo; reading and watching &amp;ldquo;no reservations&amp;rdquo; until noon&#xA;or so. I had three pints left over from the previous day, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want&#xA;to bike with that with me. So there was some morning drinking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ride followed a &amp;ldquo;pre&amp;rdquo; ravel route. It was well defined, followed an old&#xA;train line, and went straight to Bastogne. The designation &amp;ldquo;pre&amp;rdquo; meant that&#xA;it was gravel or packed earth, unlike an official route which would have been&#xA;paved. It was kind of boring, to be honest. There was no turning for 35km.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back to Belgium</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/back-to-belgium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 13:01:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/back-to-belgium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Reims -&amp;gt; Charleville-Mézière -&amp;gt; Fumay -&amp;gt; Ochamp&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m returning to camping today. And biking. I&amp;rsquo;ve literally only been away&#xA;from it for two days, but the whole idea already seems weird. And I had been&#xA;camping for two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rain and storms are coming in the rest of the week, starting in a day or two.&#xA;At great financial cost (comparatively .. 40EUR/night vs. camping for&#xA;~5EUR/night) I took a room in Bastogne for the remainder of the trip. There&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;a lot of history there. Also, with the rain coming and no real destination&#xA;beyond that, having a warm room and being able to liesurely visit the town&#xA;for a few days sounds nice. Frank arrives friday, and then we head to the&#xA;netherlands (and the bismut concert) on saturday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Day in Reims</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-day-in-reims/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 11:54:23 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-day-in-reims/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Reims&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I woke up and had coffee in the airbnb. That was a delightful way to start the&#xA;day. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be interesting going back to camping, albeit for only one&#xA;night.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started considering my next residence after this bike trip. I was planning&#xA;on Warsaw / Krakow, but actually a month rental in Paris is under 1000EUR,&#xA;and pretty centrally located. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely something to consider, but the&#xA;cost of everything will be a lot more &amp;ndash; probably 2-3x more than Poland. Just&#xA;the airbnb rental in warsaw is half of the cost of one in Paris, not even&#xA;considering food and beer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travel Companion</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/travel-companion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 09:50:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/travel-companion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Givet -&amp;gt; Revin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Today was planned as an easy day. The voie verte route starts in Givet and&#xA;passes right through Revin. In total, I was going to bike about 35km of the&#xA;route to reach my destination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within about 20min of leaving, I rode past a guy with a touring setup similar&#xA;to mine while he was having some water. A bit later I stopped to take a picture&#xA;and he rolled past me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Friendly Detour</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-friendly-detour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 12:36:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-friendly-detour/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Jemelle -&amp;gt; Houyot -&amp;gt; Beauraing -&amp;gt; Givet&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I woke up to being a little cold and it being mostly dark. How? But how? It&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;17C! I checked my phone: 6:30am. Ah, well I still got 8 hours of sleep. I&#xA;snoozed until 8:30am. The bike repair shop (remember I had unhooked my front&#xA;brakes?) didn&amp;rsquo;t open until 9:30am.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got up and packed. My breakfast was 3 belgian waffles and the remaining brown&#xA;beer from Saint Monon. They went together really well. I tried to find the guy&#xA;running the junkyard/campsite, but he was nowhere to be found. I&amp;rsquo;m now probably&#xA;wanted in the area for not paying the one euro for the campsite.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off to the Brewery</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/off-to-the-brewery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 11:41:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/off-to-the-brewery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: La Roche-en-Ardenne -&amp;gt; Hotton -&amp;gt; Jemelle&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I originally had scheduled 90 km for today. Then, upon seeing the high temp for&#xA;the day (32C), I scaled it back to 50km. I arrived in Jemelle feeling good. I&#xA;even did another 15km rountrip to get beer from Saint Monon Brewery, but now&#xA;I can feel the ride.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I followed the EV5 bike route the entire way, an international European route.&#xA;Well marked, well maintained, it was good riding. After the first 10km I&#xA;noticed my front tire was low. Nothing to be alarmed about, as I had&#xA;redistributed my gear to put more weight over the front tire.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overloaded</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/overloaded/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 19:15:50 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/overloaded/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Viersalm -&amp;gt; La Roche-en-Ardenne&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jettison some weight, or I&amp;rsquo;ll never make it to Cybertron!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Astrotrain couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more right.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The day started well, despite a 9C night that woke me up cold. Tonight it will&#xA;be cold again, but the nights get warmer after that. I&amp;rsquo;ll try stuffing extra&#xA;clothing into my sleeping bag tonight to keep warm. Like a hobo.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My plan for today was to head to&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/8nqAhSxQXtDZ2f6G6&#34;&gt;Saint-Hubert&lt;/a&gt;. My exact route was&#xA;unknown, but early in the day I passed a sign for the Lupulus brewery. It was&#xA;too early to go, but I felt inspired, and searched for other breweries in the&#xA;area. I found another about an hour away on the way to Saint-Hubert.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Smoother Path</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-smoother-path/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 15:08:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/a-smoother-path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Sourbrodt -&amp;gt; Viersalm&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It rained several times in the night. Despite my inability as an outdoorsman,&#xA;my tarp kept me dry. Except for waking up cold between 5am and 7am (cf. previous&#xA;comment on bivouac sacks), I slept well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I broke camp around 9:30am. I had only drunk two of the three beers from the&#xA;previous night, so I had a Leffe with breakfast. Breakfast was a bit of peanut&#xA;butter with some dried cranberries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rough Going</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rough-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 14:16:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/rough-going/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Lac Gileppe -&amp;gt; Sourbrodt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I broke camp early and ate my leftover sandwich that I bought in Aachen HBF. It&#xA;was bread and camembert, and would become my diet for the next three weeks&#xA;(although I did not know this at the time).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biking was brutal uphill. I had been &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; in the previous months, but&#xA;15 sets of 3min hill runs do not come close to preparing you for a 2.5 hour&#xA;uphill grind. Looking back, maybe this would have been fine if I had known&#xA;better how to shift my gears. It almost certainly would have been better if I&#xA;hadn&amp;rsquo;t overpacked. These were lessons that I learned, but looking back, I was&#xA;always going to make this first mistake. Having gone backpacking several times&#xA;I tried to pack light but felt overconfident in how much my bike could hold.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Adventure Begins</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/the-adventure-begins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 11:24:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/the-adventure-begins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location&lt;/strong&gt;: Berlin -&amp;gt; Aachen -&amp;gt; Lac Gileppe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Long travel day. After a tearful goodbye with my hetero life partner Lukas, we&#xA;were off to the races. Berlin HBF to be exact.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The train from HBF to Bad Oeynhausen (yeah, seriously) was easy. From there,&#xA;transfer to a regional train to Düsseldorf HBF. This is where it got&#xA;interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Halfway through the three or so hour ride, there was a train blocking the track&#xA;(between Oelde and Neubeckum). We got off a stop before Oelde, in&#xA;Rheda-Wiedenbrück, for the replacement bus that would take us two stops further&#xA;down the line, where we could catch the train and continue our journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Day Homeless</title>
      <link>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/first-day-homeless/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:52:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stuartnelson.xyz/posts/first-day-homeless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Berlin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Officially I&amp;rsquo;ve been unemployed for one week. Because I was still in my&#xA;apartment, still working (small project generating sales reports for bräugier),&#xA;still leading my normal life, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like anything had changed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday evening I handed over my keys to my apartment, put my bags on my bike, and became homeless.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m staying two nights with Lukas, but officially, I have no place of my own)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
